Guide to the Committee on Facilities and Environment records, 1985-1997
Duke University. University Archives
Committee on Facilities and Environment records 1985-1997
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Committee on Facilities and Environment.
3.0 linear feet Extent: 2,000 Items
The Committee on Facilities and Environment is advisory to the President and the senior officers on "all relevant issues relating to the campus or areas contiguous to campus." Collection contains minutes, memoranda, correspondence, reports, architectural and technical drawings, plot plans, studies, Polaroid photographs, and other records relating to the activities of the Committee of Facilities and Environment. Materials range in date from 1985-1997.
RL.01549
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Committee on Facilities and Environment records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1997-2000.
Historical Note
The Committee on Facilities and Environment (CFE) was formed by President Brodie in 1986 after consultation with the Academic Council. The CFE combined the Educational Facilities Committee and the Chancellor's Environmental Concerns Committee. The committee is advisory to the President and the senior officers on "all relevant issues relating to the campus or areas contiguous to campus." It reviews the administration's recommendations to the Trustee's Building and Grounds Committee. CFE is composed of six faculty and six administrators, and is co-chaired by one faculty member and one administrator. Members are appointed by the President for three year terms. The Committee meets twice a month, provided there is business to conduct.
Collection Overview
Collection contains minutes, memoranda, correspondence, reports, architectural and technical drawings, plot plans, studies, Polaroid photographs, and other records relating to the activities of the Committee of Facilities and Environment. Subjects present include campus planning, Duke Forest development, the radioactive waste site, residential quad benches, parking lots, technology center (LSRC) development, building renovations, the distribution of literature on campus, signage, and a wide variety of other matters concerning the campus and adjacent areas. Materials range in date from 1985-1997.
Collection Arrangement
Oversize materials including maps, technical drawings, and architectural rendering were separated from the collection and placed in the map cabinets.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Campus planning -- North Carolina -- Durham.; Duke University -- Buildings -- Planning.; Duke University. Committee on Facilities and Environment.; Duke University -- Facilities -- Planning
Related Material
Educational Facilities Committee records, 1962-1986.
University Archives. Duke University.
Business and Finance Division records, 1956-1983.
University Archives. Duke University.
Inventory of the Academic Council records, 1954-2000.
University Archives. Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 2 Boxes
  - Environmental concerns, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Chair 1997-1998
  - Minutes and Correspondence, 1986-1992
  - Minutes and Correspondence, 1986-1992 (Box 2)
  - Blueprint, Gating Engineering Lot, Kimley-Horn (Duke University Parking) (Opaper Map Cabinet 18)
  - Construction Plan
  - Diagram of proposed parking space (8 pages), East Campus
  - Duke Golf Course, Driving Range Update, 1988
  - Duke Residence Hall Site Plan, Walk layout, John Rogers Assosciates, June 30, 1989
  - "Duke's television tower gets cool reception, "The News and Observer" (Raleigh, NC), Wednesday July 21, 1993
  - Improvements to Student Recreation and Fitness Facilities, West Campus, 1994
  - Laundry Delivery Routes
  - Lochn'ora, Blakey Design Group, March 10, 1986
  - Policy Sciences and Public Affairs, 1989
  - Site Plan, Duke University Institute of Map
  - Tel-com Building Second Floor Renovation, 1989
  - Wannamakers Parking Area Map